（忆往昔）
我讨厌女巫
I hate witches.
他们总是把自己的体液吐的到处都是
They're always spewing their bodily fluids everywhere.
相当恶心 而且极其不卫生
It's creepy. It's downright unsanitary.
我挡不住他们
I-I can't hold them back!
- 挡住谁 - 利维坦
- Hold who back? - Leviathan!
他们就像易形者 只是更爱吃人肉
They're like shapeshifters only a lot more into eating folk.
没有东西能杀了他们
Nothing can kill 'em.
没错 萨姆·温彻斯特绝对来过这儿
Yes, sir. Sam winchester was definitely here.
我会查明他们去了哪儿
And I'll find out where they went from here.
你了解我 你知道我是什么样的人
You know me. You know the kind of person I am.
她在杀人 伙计
She's dropping bodies, man,
所以我们就得杀她
which means we got to drop her.
为了救我她杀了她母亲
She killed her own mom to save me.
她不会了
She's done.
你有没有不得不背着某人做些事吗
You ever do something behind someone's back because you had to?
你改不了你的本性
You are what you are.
你还会再杀人的
You will kill again.
对不起
I'm sorry.
（如今）
卡伦 别再质疑自己了
Karen, don't second-guess yourself.
你的房子确实漂亮极了
Yes, your house is beautiful,
但你不也反复告诉我
but didn't you tell me a million times.
那是里克心爱的房子吗
that it's Rick's dream house?
你把它卖掉就是在惩罚他 卡伦
Selling it is how you punish his ass, Karen,
经历过那么多痛苦 这不是你应得的吗
and after what you've been through, don't you deserve that?
这是你应得的 亲爱的
You do, honey.
我明天就把那些文件准备好
I'll have the papers ready tomorrow.
太好了 我为你骄傲
Yay! I'm proud of you.
再见
Bye.
我没有最好
I'm not good.
只有更好
I'm very good.
- 给你 - 谢谢
- There you are. - Thank you.
好了
All right.
要十分钟 有什么事就说话啊
10 minutes. Holler if you need anything.
克里斯
Chris!
克里…
Chri…
克里斯 快过来
Ow. Chris, get back here!
天啊 救命啊
Oh, my God. Somebody, help!
[邪恶力量 第7季第5集]
离我远一点 我说了闭嘴
Leave me alone! I said shut up!
停下
Just stop!
你改不了你的本性
You are what you are.
你还会再杀人的
You will kill again.
我不会的 我保证
I won't. I swear.
（兴隆市档案 「离奇死亡」有一个搜索结果）
跑成这德行 有人在追你啊
Somebody better be chasing you.
对身体有益处
It's good for you.
才没益处呢 看看你自己吧
No. No, it's not good for you. Look at you.
你一团糟 而且很臭
Y-you're a mess, and you stink.
在你硬装兰斯·阿姆斯特朗（七届环法冠军）时
Well, while you were out being Lance Armstrong…
- 他是骑自行车的 - 我在工作
- That would be biking. - …I was working.
你有没有听说过印第安纳州的兴隆市
You ever heard of a town called Prosperity, Indiana?
会有人听说过这小地方吗
Has anybody?
在过去的两周里有两位优秀市民死亡
Two of their fine citizens died over the past two weeks.
有一个女的 她在美发沙龙
This one chick … she, uh, roasted underneath.
被那种蜂窝式干发器烤焦了
one of those beehive hair dryers at the hair salon,
还有一人洗热水浴时被煮熟了
and this other guy boiled in a hot tub.
- 这倒是不常见 - 确实是的
- You don't see a lot of that. - No, you don't.
- 值得去调查一番 - 对
- It's worth checking out. - Yeah.
还有件事
You know, one more thing.
你到底怎么回事
What's going on with you?
我们已经谈过了 萨姆
We have had this conversation, Sam.
不 还没有
No, we haven't.
要想谈 你得… 知道吗 你得说话
See, to do that, you'd have to, uh, sort of…speak.
好吧 我这么说看你明白不
Okay, let's see if you can get this straight.
你要知道你是一个新…新的萨姆
See you're … you're new sam, right?
- 就像兰斯·阿姆斯特朗 - 他骑自行车的
- Lance Armstrong. - Biking.
而我还只是我 好吗
And, uh … and I'm still me, okay?
所以 你现在对事物的看法可能变了
All right, so … so, you might see things different now.
可能是你跑亢奋了还是什么的
Call it a runner's high or some crap,
但并不意味着我有什么事 好吗
but that doesn't mean that something's going on with me, okay?
好吧
Yeah, okay.
不行 别用「好吧」敷衍我
No, don't say, "yeah, okay, " like, "yeah, okay."
好吧
Yeah, okay.
头儿 我明白了
Yes, sir, I understand.
对 我明白温彻斯特兄弟的事
Yeah, I definitely do realize this Winchester thing.
耽搁过久了 对此我很抱歉
is taking far too long, and I'm sorry about that.
别再担心了
No worries.
我一天半后就应该能到达
I can be there in a day and a half.
好 我这就出发
Yeah, I'll hit the road now.
只是停下来补给一下
Just stopped for a quick refuel.
谢谢 这是我的荣幸
Thanks. It'll be my pleasure.
（印第安纳州 兴隆市）
非常抱歉
I'm very sorry.
我知道现在说这些让你很不好受
I-I know this is a tough time to have to talk about all this.
我已经跟那些律师 警察 保险公司
I've already been through it so many times with the lawyers,
说过很多遍了
the police, the insurance guys.
没错 我知道
Right. I know. I know.
只是 我们要进行独立的调查
We just … we have to conduct our own separate investigation.
抱歉 我知道这很难受
I'm sorry. I know it's tough.
我想问问 你妹妹有没有仇家
Can I ask you … did your sister have any enemies?
你问这个做什么
Why do you ask that?
你认为她的死不是意外事故
You think her death wasn't accidental?
不 不是这个意思 只是要考虑各种可能
No. No, no, no. We just have to consider every possibility.
有没有谁可能想要伤害她
Is there anyone who might have wanted to harm her?
你不住这儿 所以就不知道
You don't live here, so you don't know.
温蒂的人缘很好
Everyone…Loved Wendy.
她在教堂做义工
She volunteered at the church.
运作一个儿童慈善组织
She ran a group for kids.
我是她的姐姐
I was the big sister,
对她也很尊敬
and I looked up to her.
有个死者名叫卡尔·邓洛普
What about this man who died … Carl Dunlap?
- 她认不认识 - 应该不认识
- Did she know him? - I don't think so.
温蒂在房产公司工作 对吧
Well, Wendy was in real estate, right?
卡尔是建筑师
Carl was an architect.
他们会不会有过业务往来
Maybe they had some business dealings?
如果他们有过来往 我应该听说过这个名字
If they had worked together, I would've heard the name.
萨博拉探员
Agent Sambora…
如果我妹妹是被害死的 请找出凶手
If someone did this to my sister, find out who.
（约瑟芬美发店）
当时这里就只有温蒂吗
And nobody was back here but Wendy.
是的
No.
可我只离开了一分钟而已
But I was only gone for a minute.
这东西是有温限的
You can't even crank these things.
不能动手脚做改变 对吗
past a certain temperature … am I wrong?
如果烧断了保险丝什么的
If it started to blow a fuse or something,
应该会自动关闭
it would have shut down.
总而言之 你认为这种事情不可能发生
Basically, you're saying that this couldn't have happened.
总而言之 我认为这种事不可能发生
Basically, I'm saying it couldn't have happened.
保险理算员已经检查过了
The insurance adjusters already did that.
多谢提醒
Thanks for the heads-up.
什么样子的硬币
Wait. What kind of a coin?
不是美国的币种 不知道是哪儿的
It's not American. I don't know where it's from.
它插在其中一台机器的后面
It was wedged back behind one of those machines.
可能是有人丢在那里的
Somebody could have dropped it.
当然了 他们让顾客穿的
Of course, they don't have pockets.
那种长衣服没有口袋
in those robe things that they make you wear.
没想到你对做美容还很有研究
I didn't realize you were such a spa expert.
闭嘴 我那是观察仔细
Shut up. I observe with my eyes.
好吧好吧 随你怎么说
Yeah, yeah, yeah, whatever you say.
所以你认为这玩意儿肯定是某种符咒
So, you thinking it must be some kind of hex talisman?
可能吧
Maybe.
好 过来接我
All right. Pick me up.
跑步回家多好啊 兰斯
Why don't you just run home, Lance?
迪恩
Dean …
我一会儿就回来
Yeah, I'll be there in a bit.
（凡酒吧）
（杜威·斯蒂文斯建筑工程）
干嘛呢
Oh, come on …
我们对死者有什么了解
So, what do we know about the vic?
杜威·斯蒂文斯 老板 他的建筑公司
Dewey Stevens … owner, Dewey Stevens Construction,
是这儿最大的
biggest outfit in town.
他是扶轮社会员 卫理公会教徒 男高音
Rotarian, methodist, tenor,
做山核桃派的手艺一流 患哮喘病
blue-ribbon pecan pie champ, asthmatic.
这个社区很小
We're a close-knit community.
这位社区的重要人物
So, this, um, pillar of the community …
挨钉子之前 他正在撒尿 对吧
He was taking a leak before he, uh, sprung a few?
员工都已经走了 这里也关闭了
The crew had gone for the day. Site was shut down.
除了眼睛里的钉子 还有什么异常发现
Anything unusual besides the nails in the eyes?
我们
Well, we're…
还在调查射钉枪是怎么通电的
Still trying to figure out where they plugged in the nail gun,
因为卡车上没有发电机
seeing as there's no generator on the truck.
好吧 等调查出来了就告诉我
Well, when you figure that out, let me know.
又是一个人见人爱的死者
So, another victim everybody likes.
有人不爱
Not everybody.
又一起不可能发生的死亡事件
Another physically impossible death.
- 你有什么想法 - 耍杂技的干的吗
- You got any ideas? - Cirque du soleil?
想起来了 又找到一枚硬币
Oh, I, uh, found another one of these,
跟烫发烤头机那里的一样
just like at the, uh, the hair-dryer/brain-roast.
我发现了这些死者之间的关联
And I found a connection with all the vics.
从电邮日志来看 那个做房地产的女孩温蒂
These e-mail logs show Wendy, the real-estate chick,
那个建筑师卡尔 和这个杜威
Carl, the architect, and this Dewey guy.
曾合作过一个购物中心的项目
were all working on a shopping-center project together.
我们之前怎么不知道呢
Why didn't we know about that?
不知道为什么 项目突然中断了
Well, it all fell apart for some reason.
这些邮件来来往往的
I mean, there are these e-mails back and forth,
收发相当频繁 突然间就这么中止了
pretty hot and heavy, and suddenly they just stopped.
也就是说 参与这项工程的人都死了
So, everybody working on this project has died?
还没全死
Well, not yet.
他们都是给一个叫做唐·斯达克的
They were working with a developer,
开发商打工的
a guy named Don Stark.
唐·斯达克 我怎么听过这个名字
Don Stark? Why do I know that name?
（唐纳德·斯达克 兴隆市基金会创始人）
兄弟 这个斯达克还真是德高望重啊
Man, this Stark guy is really plugged in, huh?
所以 只要是这个…
So, all the players in this …
这个购物中心工程的参与者
this shopping-center project.
不是被油炸 水煮就是被当成肉串烤了
have either fried, boiled, or kebabbed.
下一个可能是他
He could be next.
不是吧
Really?
还喝瓶装酒
From a freaking flask?
你成圣诞坏公公了吗
What are you, bad Santa?
- 再说我们在工作 - 我们总在工作
- On the job? - We're always on the job.
好吧 鲍比回复邮件了
All right. Bobby e-mailed back.
我给他发了几张你发现的硬币的照片
I sent him a few pics of those coins you found.
他说上面的文字是罗马尼亚的斯拉夫字母
He says the writing is Romanian Cyrillic,
只在十五世纪中期到十九世纪使用过
used only in the mid-15th to the 19th century.
这是枚古老的瓦拉几亚硬币
Apparently, it's an antique Wallachian ducat.
那我们是要找一个高龄罗马尼亚人吗
So, we're looking for an old Romanian?
只有我觉得这个很怪异吗
You know, is it just me, or is this really weird?
我之前见到过这种情况
I've seen this once before,
有个地方一片的植物都死了
where t-the plants are all dead in one spot.
在哪儿
Where?
一张上面有着温蒂·古德逊照片的公交站长凳
A bus bench with Wendy Goodson's picture on it.
我不是专家 可是我不觉得
I mean, I'm no expert, but I don't think.
植物该变成这样
plants are supposed to act like this.
要是联调局都出动了
If the bureau's involved,
我猜你认为这三个人是被谋杀的
I assume you think all three were murdered.
看上去是那么回事 没错
It's looking that way, yes.
斯达克先生 你曾与这三位死者
Now, Mr. Stark, you had a relationship.
都打过交道 对吗
with all three victims, isn't that correct?
我在商界结识的他们 可以这么说吧
Oh, I knew them in business circles, I guess, sure.
你们都曾参与过一个购物中心的项目
And you were all involved in a, uh, a-a shopping-center project.
可为什么项目落空了
Why'd that fall through?
这种事常有发生
Uh, t-these things happen.
詹妮
Oh. Jenny.
这两位先生从联调局而来
These gentlemen are from the FBI.
詹妮·克莱恩 我的助手
Jenny Klein, my assistant.
你好
Hi, there.
唐 我去洗衣店了
Okay, Don, I'm off to the cleaner's,
然后去养蜂人公司
and then I'm gonna stop at beaman, beaman, and beaman.
处理修订合同的事
for the revised contracts.
快去快回 你知道很多事没你不行的
Hurry on back. You know how things fall apart without you.
我给你烤了些杯型蛋糕 椰子味的
Oh, I baked you some cupcakes … coconut.
椰子味的 你对我真是太好了
Coconut … you're too good to me, Jenny.
一会儿见
Oh. I'll see you soon.
她会烤杯型蛋糕
She bakes cupcakes.
令人垂涎
Yummy.
能告诉我洗手间在哪吗
You know what? Could you point me to the restroom?
我刚喝多了咖啡
I had a little bit too much java.
沿着走廊 在拐角处
Yeah, around the corner, down the hall.
谢谢
Thanks.
一般像这样的情况
So, uh, usually in cases like these …
有过这样的情况吗
Are there cases like these?
说出来吓你一跳
Oh, you'd be surprised.
我们从最基本的开始着手
Uh, we start out with the basics.
你有什么商业竞争对手吗
You have any business rivals?
当然 多了去了 房地产界很残酷的
Sure, tons. You know, real estate's brutal.
你倒是答得爽快
Well, that was easy.
但是 我对这里的爱有目共睹
On the other hand, i've demonstrated my love for this town,
可以毫不夸张地说
and I think it's safe to say.
我在这里的作为是受人敬重的
I'm respected for what I've done here.
这才是我的真正的珍宝
Yeah, one of my real treasures.
（年度市民 唐·斯达克）
「致唐 赶尽杀绝 唐·特朗普」
"To Don … take no prisoners. D. Trump."
特朗普建筑
The trumpster! Wow.
如我所说 成功衍生了激烈的竞争
Like I said, success breeds fierce competition,
但最终 这里的每个人都敬重我
but in the end, everyone here respects and admires me.
包括你的妻子吗
Including your wife?
抱歉 我们听说你们在闹分居 对吗
Sorry. It's just, we heard the two of you were splitting up, right?
没错 我们…我们确实听说了
Yeah, that's, uh … that's what we heard.
是的 玛姬和我现在关系有些紧张
Yeah, Maggie and I are going through a tough time.
确实在分居 不过是暂时的
It's a separation … temporary.
有时候 两个人会疏远
Sometimes, you know, you grow apart.
不能怪任何人
It's no one's fault.
那你会怎么形容
Now, how would you describe the, uh …
你跟你妻子之间的问题呢
the issues between you and your wife?
你懂的 只是那种夫妻间的误会罢了
Just one of those marital misunderstandings, you know.
不 抱歉 我不太明白
No, I'm sorry. I don't.
就是那种不明所以 说不清楚的争执
It's one of those vague, hard-to-define passages.
她抓到你偷腥 是吧
She caught you cheating, huh?
我注意到
I couldn't help but notice, uh,
你跟你助理之间的挺来劲的
things were kind of cordial between you and your assistant.
跟女士们的关系很好吧 斯达克先生
Pretty good with the ladies there, Mr. Stark?
真是痛并快乐着 不是吗
It's a blessing and a curse, isn't it?
伙计们 我人缘很好
Guys, I'm a people person,
我也欣赏活力充沛 自信满满的女士
and I admire dynamic, confident women.
只是欣赏吗
"Admire"?
我最近的确
Okay, look … it's true I had a recent…
跟我的生意伙伴有点事
little thing with a business associate,
但仅此而已
but that's all it was.
- 东西 - 没错
- A "Thing"? - Yeah.
说得像只鞋或者高尔夫俱乐部
Like a … like a shoe or a golf club.
- 就像华夫饼烤模 - 对
- Right. Like a waffle iron. - Yeah.
不 唐 妻子们通常都把外遇看得
Yeah. No, see, Don, uh, wives generally think of an affair.
比「事」要严重得多
as something more than a thing.
是的 所以玛姬发现这事的时候
Yes, and when Maggie found out about it,
她需要分开一段时间 只是暂时的
she needed some time off, temporarily.
那如果我们猜
Now, if we were to guess.
那个生意伙伴是温蒂·古德逊
that the, uh, uh, business associate was Wendy Goodson,
能算中头奖吗
would we win the weekend trip to Maui?
不 她的死跟外遇无关
No, her death had nothing to do with the affair.
我们在她死前很久就结束了
It was over long before her accident.
如果是意外致死的话
If it was an accident.
你不会是在暗示玛姬是幕后黑手吧
You're not implying that Maggie was behind this.
不 我们什么都没有暗示
No, we're not implying anything.
我们只是在说 你要小心一点
We're just saying… you should be careful.
请她吃晚餐并且道歉
And take her to dinner and apologize.
对了 低声下气点 不会少块肉的
Yeah, and, uh, grovel. Wouldn't hurt.
他们有一堆巫术用品
Found a bunch of hex junk in their stuff …
显然她挺有研究
Clearly her thing.
而且她衣柜空荡荡的
And the empty closet didn't seem like.
看来她近期是不会搬回来了
she was coming back anytime soon.
唐欣赏温蒂 神圣地欣赏
So, Don admires Wendy, biblically,
温蒂莫名其妙地死了
Wendy dies weird,
被轻视的妻子则喜欢黑巫术
and the scorned wife is into the dark stuff.
而唐还全然不知
While Don's just in the dark.
还真有点像《家有仙妻》（美国老电视剧）
Hmm. It's kind of like "Bewitched".
唐就是戴霖（男主角） 完全不知情
You know, Don's Darrin, doesn't even know it.
之前都挺喜剧 直到你出轨
A lot laughs until, uh, you cheat on your wife.
用《家有仙妻》作比喻 你不是吧
A "Bewitched" reference. Really?
兄弟 翻拍电影可是妮可·基德曼演的
Dude, Nicole Kidman was in the remake.
那个红发美女 好吗
Redhead. Hello!
看看这些枯死的植物
Look at all these dead plants.
就跟房地产小姐那里
Huh. It's kind of like the real-estate lady's place.
还有唐的雕塑那里一样
and Don's statue thing.
如果她够强大
You know, if she's strong enough,
而且被惹毛了
just being pissed off.
就有能力冲他们发泄不满了
is enough to send some pretty bad vibes their way.
差不多就是一个怒发冲冠
Literally kill off everything around her.
就能撂倒一片
just by pms-ing at it.
完全不恐怖啊
Eeh. That's not creepy at all.
鲍比 我是迪恩 听着
Bobby, hey, it's Dean. Listen…
温彻斯特 真搞笑
Winchester. Yeah, very funny.
我们需要一个咒语
So, we need our kind of terminix.
对付女巫
A witch.
我们现在开车去她家了解具体情况
Yeah, we're headed over to her place to get you some more specifics,
如果你可以
so if you could just, uh …
谢 谢了
Y… thank y…
他在着手准备了
He's on it.
（拉尔森地产）
（詹妮弗·克莱恩）
唐 兄弟 管好你的小弟弟
Don, keep it in your pants, man.
线路忙
All circuits are busy.
斯达克太太
Mrs. Stark.
能谈谈吗
Could I have a moment?
当然
Of course.
你能等会再来吗 大概 过半个小时
Um, would you mind coming back in, say, a half an hour?
现在真不是个好时机
It's just a really bad time right now.
我得跟你谈谈 这真的很重要
It's very important that I talk to you.
当然 我也很乐意
Of course, and I'm happy to.
只是我现在有急事要办 请你等会再来
I'm just in the middle of an emergency, so please come back.
谢谢
Thank you!
很抱歉
I'm sorry …
下肢不宁综合症
Uh… Restless Leg Syndrome.
剧透了 詹妮·克莱恩是下一个
Spoiler alert … Jenny Klein's next.
把她的照片从巫术祭台上拿下来了
Swiped her photo off a hex deck,
但是玛姬最终都会发现照片不见了的
but Maggie's gonna notice it's gone eventually.
我们得赶去詹妮家
We got to get over to Jenny's.
[咒语]
找到那枚硬币
Find the coin, now!
快点 萨姆
Come on, Sam!
我的蛋糕里面有跳动的小心脏
There were tiny beating hearts in my cupcakes,
我的蛋糕里面有心脏
there were hearts in my cupcakes,
hearts in my cupcakes!
前所未闻啊 我的蛋糕里怎么会有心脏啊
That's never happened before! Hearts in my cupcakes!
要我打昏她吗
Should I slug her?
让她冷静会
Give it a second.
我的天啊 刚刚发生了什么
Oh, my god. What just happened?
你被下咒了
You were hexed.
下咒
"Hexed"?
你们是谁
Who are you people?
我该怎么办
What the hell do I do?
现在你要做的就是进去打包行李
What you do is you go in there and you pack a bag,
上车 走人
you get in your car, and you go.
- 去哪里 - 随便你
- Go where? - It doesn't matter.
随便开出去五六百里就可以了
500 or 600 miles ought to do it.
你惹怒了某些个强大的人
You got someone real powerful real pissed,
他们现在要除掉你
and they're trying to get rid of you now.
与此同时
In line with that,
你最好缓一缓你和唐·斯达克的关系
you might want to cool things with Don Stark.
唐·斯达克
Don Stark?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你和唐
You and Don.
那什么
You know.
"You know"?
没有什么那什么
There's no "You know."
没有吗
No?
唐·斯达克是我的老板
Don Stark is my boss.
仅此而已
That's it.
天啊 他可结婚了
He's married, for god's sake.
是啊 那么
Yeah, well…
我和唐·斯达克
Me and Don Stark.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
把这些桌子往中间靠靠
Bunch these tables more in the middle.
让油画间的空间更大点
Give me a more air between paintings.
你好 玛姬 签收下花吧
Hey. Maggie, can you sign for the flowers?
我检查过了 没问题
I've checked them. They're fine.
谢谢你 苏 没有你我该怎么办
Thank you, Sue. What would I do without you?
不客气 我喜欢帮忙
Oh, please, I like helping.
谁叫我们是好朋友呢
What are best friends for?
只是唐的事 实在是太让人费心了
It's just been so tough to focus with Don, the whole mess.
就像往你心上扎刀子 是吗
It's like he put a knife right in your heart, isn't it?
没错
Yes.
我是不是不该告诉你他和温蒂的事情
Was I wrong to tell you about him and Wendy?
不 不
No. No.
你觉得我会宁愿你袖手旁观
You think I'd want you to stand by.
看着我被他耍吗
and watch him make a fool of me?
- 我爱你的做法 - 我也爱你
- I love you for what you did. - I love you, too.
不 不 不 静物不放在那儿
No, no, no. The still life doesn't go there.
往左边放
It goes on the left side.
我们需要
So, uh, we're gonna need, uh,
每个桌子中间放个装饰品 后边也需要两个
one centerpiece on each of the tables and two at the back.
- 唐 - 我老婆呢
- Don. - Where's my wife?
你是说要和你离婚的那个吗
You mean the one who's divorcing you?
苏 我知道你迫不及待想让我滚
Sue, I know you can hardly wait until I'm out of the picture,
我也知道在玛姬耳边撒谎
and I know it's been a thrill.
说悄悄话让你激动不已
whispering lies into Maggie's ear.
那些可不是谎话 是吗 唐
Oh, but they weren't lies, were they, Don?
我只犯了一个错 一个
I made one mistake … one.
我非常怀疑
I sincerely doubt that.
这是玛姬和我的事
This is between Maggie and me.
与你无关
It has nothing to do with you.
你想干嘛 唐
What do you want, Don?
我想和你谈谈
I'd like to speak with you.
有话快说
Make it quick.
好的
Okay.
你知道吗 玛姬
You know what, Maggie?
我觉得我很有耐心了
I think I've been patient.
你也找到乐子了
And you've had your fun.
温蒂的事 你耍的花招挺厉害
It was very creative, the thing with Wendy,
够了 收手吧
But, you know, enough is enough.
不 唐 不够 还远远不够
No, Don, enough is not enough, not even close.
你想干吗 杀了我吗
What do you want, my oysters on a tray?
既然你都这么说了
Well, now that you mention it …
事实是 这些都不是我的错
The fact is, none of this was my fault!
如果你能多陪陪我
Maybe if you'd been around a little more.
别管这些艺术品 慈善 还有那个碎嘴的苏
But between the art and the charity and that evil bitch Sue,
我现在几乎不存在于你的生活中
I was edged right out of your life.
大人物先生
Oh, boo-hoo, Mr.Big shot,
「我得把名字烙在镇上每件公共设施上」先生
Mr."I got to put my name on every public works in town."
我们的婚姻里有三个人
There was three of us in this marriage,
我 你 以及你的自负
me, you, and your ego.
那才是问题所在 唐
That was the problem, don.
不好意思了 我要去安排慈善活动
So, excuse me. I have a charity event to arrange.
两个联调局的人来过 问了些事
Two FBI agents came by, asking questions.
猎人 甜心 他们是猎人
Hunters, sweetheart … that's what they are.
看来你对我的安全还挺关心的
I can see you're terribly concerned for my safety,
但是别担心 我能处理好
but don't worry … I'll take care of it.
玛姬 别干了 听到了吗
Maggie, this stops. you hear me?
立刻收手
As of now.
你命令我的时候真可爱
You're so cute when you try to tell me what to do.
现在她越来越恶心了
Now she's just getting nasty.
杀死女友是一回事
Killing the girlfriend is one thing,
把这雕像弄爆
But his commemorative bust?
这可过头了
That's got to hurt.
她会干掉整个镇子的人 迪恩
She'll take the whole town out, dean.
她可不管谁挡道
She don't care who gets in the way.
鲍比 找到什么了
Bobby. What do you got?
是吗 这个对她管用吗
Yeah. You think it'll take her out?
好吧
All right.
不用写下来 我记得住 继续吧
No, I don't need to write it down. I'll remember. Go ahead.
什么 等下 等下
The … wait. Hang on. Hang on.
说
Yeah.
等等 什么 慢点 慢点
Wait, what… Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
那最后一个是什么
What was the … what was that last one?
好的
Right.
我记得住 没问题
I'll remember. It's fine.
大家好 欢迎你们的到来
Hello, everyone, and thanks for coming.
你们大多数人都清楚
Most of you know.
慈善和艺术是我的两大最爱
that philanthropy and art are my two passions,
但是我们 别放那
but what we've … not there!
冰在哪 人们马上就来了
Where is the ice? people will be here in seconds.
我们今晚在此展示的东西
What we've assembled here tonight.
也许是我今生最大的成就 不是显摆
may be my crowning achievement, not to be immodest.
看吧 我就说
See? I told you.
一切完美无暇
Everything's perfect.
你正好提醒我了
Yeah, you just reminded me.
我要去检查下手指三明治
I have to check on the finger sandwiches.
- 老兄 - 派
- Dude. - Pie.
这不会是
That is …
鸡爪 配方里要求的
Chicken feet, just like the recipe calls for.
- 屠夫家的冰箱坏了 - 我闻出来了
- Butcher's fridge is down. - I can smell that.
据说是电力出了问题
Says the power's been wonky.
他损失了大量商品
And that he's lost so much product,
都快要付不出租金了
He probably won't make rent.
街上每家店都是
Ditto every shop on the block …
到处都有管道破裂和停电
Nothing but burst pipes and blackouts.
他说好像是一夜之间
He says it's like all of a sudden,
整个镇子的染上了晦气
the town ran out of luck.
巧合吗
So, coincidence, right?
可能吧
Uh…Yeah.
枯花现在不叫事儿了
We're past the point of dead flowers.
那能怎么办 我猜巫婆火人了
What can I say? I guess the witch is pissed.
好吧 我们还是赶快把这个弄完吧
All right, let's, we better get a move on here.
不如你 你把这爪子拿走
Why don't you just … can you take the feet?
敬我们
To us.
没你我绝对做不到
I couldn't have done it without you.
敬我们
To us.
真恶心
That is disgusting!
不
No.
别动我的画
Not my paintings.
玛姬 这怎么回事
Maggie? what is going on?
是他做的
He did this.
他怎么能这样
How could he?
他知道这对我很重要
He knew what this meant to me.
你是说唐吗
Do you mean don?
唐操控了这一切
Don rigged all this?
- 是的 - 怎么做的
- Yes! - But how?
相信我就是了
Just trust me.
他想让我伤心
He wants to hurt me.
我告诉过你 他是个混蛋
I told you … he's a dick.
但我们能挺过去
But we'll get through this.
因为你还有爱你的人
Because you have people who love you,
而他无法将这些人夺走
and he can't take that away from you.
好吧 唐纳德
Fine, donald.
来开战吧
It's war.
怎么回事
What the hell?
清理下7号厅吧
Clean-up on aisle 7.
她应该不会这样破坏自己的拍卖吧
Okay, I don't guess she'd do this to her own auction.
显然是有个恨她入骨的人
No, obviously it was someone who hated her guts.
想让她的聚会泡汤
And wanted her party trashed.
唐·斯达克
Don Stark.
这小子自己也是个巫师
So, the mister's a witch, himself.
意味着我们要对付不只一个气头上的巫婆
That means we got not just one pissed-off witch.
他俩要上演《错对冤家》了（福克斯1989年电影）
We've got two. It's full-on "War of the Roses".
《家有仙妻》现在不那么喜剧了
"Bewitched" just got a lot less funny.
悲剧得像他们换掉戴琳的时候
It's like when they switched Darrins.
她去哪儿了
Where is she?
她会来的
She'll be here.
他们已经干掉了对方
They've been throwing thunderbolts.
最喜欢的玩具
at each other's favorite toys.
现在就剩他们两个了
There's nothing left to destroy but each other.
- 要爆发肯定是在这里了 - 希望如此
- This is basically ground zero. - I hope so.
要把两个都干掉
We're gonna need them both.
得要他们出现在同一个地方
in the same place if we're gonna take them down.
隐蔽 队长
Screens up, Captain.
- 来一杯吗宝贝 - 边儿去
- Want one, sweetie? - Shove it.
不是你死就是我亡
We are so having it out right now.
[咒语]
我来猜猜
Let me guess …
鸡爪子吗
Chicken feet?
不够冰喔
Not chilled?
显然你们不能离开这个房间了
For obvious reasons, you won't be leaving this room.
你们能离开 只是不能活着离开
Well, you will be leaving … just not alive.
玛姬
Maggie?
[咒语]
- 好吧 备用计划 - 啥是备用计划
- Okay, plan "B". - What's plan "B"?
说话
Talking.
现在吗 真的吗
Now? Really?
显然这是夫妻吵架
This is obviously a domestic dispute.
如果我们搞不死他们 就劝劝他们吧
So if you can't kill them, counsel them.
是啊 你猜怎么着 不是我的专长啊
Yeah. You know what? Not my area!
[咒语]
好了 好了 好了 那个
Okay, okay, okay. Uh…
很显然你们两个
Look … obviously, you two.
完全有能力干掉对方
are capable of wiping each other out, right?
但你们没那么做
But you haven't, huh?
也就是说你们两个
Which means that you two …
还珍惜你们之间的感情
you still value whatever it is you got.
还希望和彼此继续下去
A-and you want keep that dance going.
也许 也许是上天的惩罚
Maybe it's … maybe it's punishment.
或许这就是病态的 混乱的 色情的
Maybe it's … it's sick, messed-up, erotic,
重口味的 掐死你温柔那种爱情
kinky, "clamps and feathers" kind of love.
好了 好了 说得太深刻了兄弟
Okay, okay, t-that's … that's going way too deep, there, cowboy.
他想说的是 你们两个
Look, what he's trying to say is that … is that you two …
不管怎样 你们心连着心
whatever it is you have, you're bonded.
你脑子秀逗了吗
Are you out of your mind?
他出轨了 羞辱了我
He cheated on me, humiliated me.
我们不是说他所做的都对
We're not trying to say what don did was right.
可一旦关系出现裂痕
When a relationship cracks,
一般双方都是有责任的
usually both parties have a hand in it.
说得好
Indeed.
你还替他狡辩吗
You're defending him?
好了 好了
Okay, okay!
好了 没人能替他狡辩
Okay, look … n-nobody can defend Don.
是不是 真的
Right? Uh, totally.
我们懂你觉得他背叛了你 也确实如此
But, uh, we get that you feel betrayed…Because you were.
别奉承她
Don't suck up to her.
我确实受到了背叛 他们所有人
I was betrayed by all of them.
卡尔把你介绍给温蒂 杜威为你掩护
Carl introduced you to Wendy. Dewey covered for you.
- 温蒂和你上床 - 好了好了
- Wendy did you! - Okay, okay, look …
我得说我觉得唐说他很后悔和温蒂的事
I got to say I-I don't think Don was lying when he said.
这不是谎话
he regrets the whole Wendy thing.
事
"Thing"?
坐下吧你
Sit down.
对 外遇 你是对的 这很不好
Yeah, affair … that's right, terrible.
我想他唯一的后悔是被发现
I think the only thing he regrets is getting caught.
温蒂对我无足轻重
Wendy was nothing to me.
我们很快就结束了
It was over as soon as it started.
她不过是其中一个而已
She was part of a pattern, okay?
这八百年都是这样
I've had 800 years of this.
别让我提起文艺复兴时候的事
Do not make me bring up the Renaissance!
你还敢说
You're one to talk.
1492年的事有印象吗
1492 ring any bells?
那小子都要去远航了
The man was about to set sail!
他搞不好会从世界边缘掉下去
He could possibly fall off of the edge of the earth.
我很可怜他 那你的理由是什么
I took pity. So, what's your excuse?
我说了 我和那个姓梅第奇（文艺复兴时期佛罗伦萨著名家族）的没关系
I told you … nothing happened with the Medici chick!
你一直都是个大醋坛子
You've always been insanely jealous.
有果必有因 詹妮 温蒂
Oh, I wonder why! Jenny. Wendy.
我跟詹妮更没什么了 她只是我助理
Jenny? Nothing happened with Jenny. She's just my assistant.
这是事实
That's true.
她跟我们说了 只是助理
She, uh … she told us … just an assistant.
是真的吗
Is that true?
当然 我发誓 宝贝
Yes, I swear it, babe.
我绝不会那样
I would never.
我错了
I made a mistake.
对不起 玛姬
I'm sorry, Maggie.
看见没 看见没
See? See?
你们…终于能好好谈谈了
Guys, guys… You're talking.
这么多年 你们把愤怒和失望
All these years, you … you buried your anger.
憋在心里 直到这毁了你们的感情
and your disappointment till it tore you apart.
其实你们只需要好好谈谈
All you needed to do was talk.
我的脑壳也不会挨那一遭了
And I would have missed the nuking that my melon just took.
大家都不想的
Well, who wants that?
- 妙招啊 - 谢谢
- Nice touch. - Thank you.
他说的没错
He's right.
我不会杀你
I couldn't kill you.
这辈子我只想要你 玛格
All I ever wanted is you, Mags.
我一直都爱着你
I've been crushing on you since forever.
我只想执子之手 与子不老
You're the woman that I want to never grow old with.
我也绝不会杀你 唐
I could never murder you either, Don.
这很疯狂…但却是实话
It's crazy… But true.
谁能喊个停吗
Somebody want to call these things off?
抱歉 打扰下
Ex… excuse me!
省省吧
Oh, give me a break.
我可什么也没说
I didn't say anything.
今天太不容易了
It's been a long day.
还没完事呢
And it's not over yet.
萨姆
Hi, Sam.
迪恩
Hi, Dean.
我们认识你吗
Do we know you?
我当然认识你们 你们是死人
Well, I definitely know you. You're the dead guys.
至少马上就是了
Well, you will be in a minute.
不好意思 你不够强大
Sorry. You're a bit outmatched.
唐
Don.
谢谢 我们欠你的
Thank you. We owe you.
上帝啊 那什么玩意儿
Good god. What is that thing?
我想我们应该查个明白
I guess we should be figuring that out.
在我们的待查事件簿上
It is on our to-do list.
找个无底洞 把尸体处理掉
You know, find a bottomless pit and drop it in.
咒语只能维持数日
Spell only lasts for a few days.
你怎么会来这
Uh, what are you even doing here?
显然 是来救你们命的
Apparently, saving your lives …
两次了
Twice.
拿到了
Got it.
玛姬 不是吧
Maggie? Seriously?
她要置我们于死地吗
She was gonna kill us?
我们还刚挽救了你们的婚姻
We just saved your damn marriage.
没错 可公平来说
Yeah, but to be fair,
你们也试图杀她来着
you also tried to kill her.
你们也知道
You know how she is.
她发起火来的样子
when she gets a bug up her ass.
真叫人不得不爱 不是吗
Got to love her, right?
好了
Right.
记住 无底洞
Bottomless pit.
再见
Ciao.
可以转移他了
Yeah, he's ready for transport.
你最好有地方安置他 鲍比
I just hope you got someplace you can put him, Bobby.
好的
All right.
我们得出发了 你准备好了吗
We should hit the road. You ready?
你之前…
Hey, were you, um …
有在听今晚斯达克夫妇的谈话吗
were you listening to the Starks tonight?
听了一点儿
Uh, a little,
在我没被煽向墙面或是被蜜蜂群殴期间
when I wasn't getting slammed into a wall or stung by bees.
你注意到他们是怎么…
You notice how they, uh … you know,
怎么敞开心扉
how they … how they opened up,
一吐为快的吗
got everything off their chest?
恭喜 你成功推销了你那套歪理论
Yeah. Kudos on selling them that crap.
那不是歪理论 迪恩 是有用的
It wasn't crap, Dean. It worked.
萨姆 我现在非常 非常 非常累
Sam, I am so very, very, very, very…very, very tired …
迪恩 不管你愿不愿意
Dean, like it or not,
你不想说出的那些心事不会自行消失
the stuff you don't talk about doesn't just go away.
而是会越来越沉重
It builds up,
就比如现在折磨着你的心事
like whatever's eating at you right now.
我总是有心事
There's always something eating at me.
我就这样
That's who I am.
发生了一些事情
Something happens,
我就觉得是我的责任
I feel responsible, all right?
林德伯格婴儿案 那事责任在我
The Lindbergh baby … that's on me.
失业 由我而起
Unemployment … my bad.
这不是我想说的
That's not what I'm talking about.
那你究竟想说什么
Well, then what the hell are you talking about?
我是指你不想说的那件心事
I'm talking about whatever you're not telling me about.
迪恩 没关系
Look, Dean, it's fine.
你完全可以一吐为快
You can unload.
我不就是干这个的吗
That's kind of what I'm here for.
我们没问题的 可以交心的 不是吗
I mean… We're good, right?
我们没问题
We're good.